imd.org 2017-12-07

# Privacy Policy | IMD Business School

IMD Privacy policy

At IMD, we care about your privacy. The purpose of this privacy policy is to provide clear notice about personal and other information collected through your interactions with IMD, notably through our different IMD websites including mobile applications and online platforms such as Global Leader Index, the Alumni Directory, the One IMD Collaboration Platform you can access through our maingate http://www.imd.org (altogether “IMD Websites”), as well as through correspondence with IMD.

The intended audience of our Websites does not include children; therefore, we do not knowingly capture personal data from children. If you believe your child has provided us with personally identifiable information, and you would like to have the information removed, please contact us at: [privacy@imd.org](mailto:privacy@imd.org?subject=Privacy%20policy%20and%20data%20question)

Please however take note that some areas of our Websites may have specific terms and conditions, including privacy statements that relate to their specific content, practices and use of personal information. When visiting any areas of our Websites, it is recommended that users consult any other additional privacy statements available.

This version was released on 19 January 2017

#### What Data we Collect when you browse IMD Websites

Your interactions with IMD Websites may lead you to provide us with different type of personal information depending upon your access and use to our Websites. Any such information is provided at your own choice and shall affirmatively and deliberately be released by you in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

The provision of such information may take place in the generic ways defined below. Should you want further details on the exact data collected, please contact [privacy@imd.org](mailto:privacy@imd.org?subject=Privacy%20policy%20and%20data%20question).

**A. Browsing**

You can access our Website home page and browse our site without having to register in any way. When you merely browse our Websites, we do not collect any personally identifiable information.  
In the absence of any registration on IMD Websites, we only collect basic anonymized information about your computer and connection, including the type of Internet browser you use, time spent on IMD Websites, the pages visited and the IP address of your internet service provider (ISP).  
We will only use the information described above to monitor and improve our Websites, ensure that we provide you with the proper information, and for security purposes.

**B. Brochure downloads**

Different areas of our IMD Websites enable you to download brochures without requiring the creation of an account. In that case, you will need to provide us with the following basic mandatory information: name, first name and email address as well as, upon your own choice, your country of residence and phone number.

**C. Account creation**

Creating an IMD account will require you to provide us with the following mandatory information: title, name, first name and email address.

At your own choice, you may then create a profile and provide us with further personal information such as: your nationality, Linkedin profile URL, private contact details (mobile phone number, address, country), your career biography, your interests, your current employment details and employment history, as well as your educational background.

In creating an account, you become an IMD Web Community Member.

**D. IMD Global Leader Index**

The creation of an IMD account shall automatically enable you to join the IMD Global Leader Index community. Joining the IMD Global Leader Index shall then entitle you to provide us with further information related to your career and professional competencies, on a purely voluntarily basis.

You are however at all time in full control to decide if you want to be visible or not on the Platform, and to which extent you agree to have the information disclosed to be visible to others IMD Web Community Members, which, by default, shall be visible to all at the exception of your IMD Global Leader Index Card Page.

**E. Application form/Participants**

When you apply to one of IMD programs, you will be requested to provide us with different types of data, including: private contact details (name, first name, email address, mail address, phone numbers), current employment details, employment history, interest and educational background.

**F. Linkedin profile**

Through your LinkedIn account, in which case IMD shall in any case only be entitled to access the LinkedIn information you agree to grant us access to on a case by case basis

**G. Online Services**

Your use of IMD Websites may enable you to benefit from different online services such as surveys, applications etc. (Online Services) provided either directly by IMD or through subcontractors. By downloading, access and/or use of these Online Services, you expressly consent to our collecting of the personal data required to enable you to benefit from these Online Services. IMD shall at all time ensure that such third party providers (if any) comply with data protection laws and regulations.

What Data we collect through your correspondence with us

If you contact IMD by mail, email or any official IMD communication channel, or expressly share information with us in relation to inquiries you may have, we will keep a record of the information you provide us solely for the purpose of responding to your inquiry.

Purposes

The personal information collected as defined above shall be used for the following general purposes:

  * Enables us to increasingly personalize your experience on our Websites
  * Enables us to offer you IMD program and service recommendations in line with your profile
  * Enables you to fully benefit from the concerned Website functionalities, notably the IMD Global Leader Index platform.

Sharing

The above mentioned personal information you voluntarily and deliberately provide to us may be shared in the following ways:

**A. In general**

We do not sell, rent, lease or otherwise make available any personal information to third parties except as set forth above or with your prior consent. We reserve the right to disclose information to authorities when required to do so in connection with legal or regulatory proceedings.

IMD may however use subcontractors to perform part of the services it provides to you. As a result, your data may be shared with such subcontractors, solely and exclusively, in order to support IMD in performing its services. Any data shared are deleted by these subcontractors, once their services in relation to your data has been performed.

IMD shall ensure that any subcontractors shall review and accept to comply with IMD internal privacy policy.  
In addition to the above, your data will be shared in the following way for the specific services defined below:

**B. Global Leader Index Platform**

  * With other members of the same platform as you may consider appropriate depending upon your privacy settings.

**C. Application form/Participants**

  * With any third-party organizations and individuals delivering small portions of IMD programs and services. The personal information shared is limited to your contact details (name, first name, email address, mail address, phone numbers), and is for the sole purpose of delivering IMD programs and services.
  * Should you have been a participant to an IMD program and upon expiration of such program, with alumni clubs notably, club presidents, their club committees and club administrators, for the purposes of local and regional alumni activities in the way set out below.

Links on IMD Websites

Our Websites contain links to other sites. Although the IMD logo and references to IMD may appear on some third-party websites, please be aware that IMD is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by our Websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Websites and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

Data Security

IMD takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit personal information via IMD Websites, their information is protected both online and offline. For example, when our registration form asks users to enter personal information, the information is protected during transmission by an industry-standard high level of encryption - 256-bit SSL. You can examine our security certificate and learn more about this security from our security provider.

Any information you provide to us is stored on:

  * Servers hosted in Switzerland at the IMD premises, which are controlled by IMD in a secure environment, in a locked facility so as to safeguard your information and avoid any data loss to the extent possible, or in the European Economic Area (EEA) zone in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.
  * Servers owned and/or controlled by IMD for the purpose of processing data collected by third parties on behalf of IMD, or in the EEA zone in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

Although your information shall at all time be stored in Switzerland or EEA, such information may be processed in accordance with applicable laws and regulations and our Privacy Policy from outside EEA by our different service providers.

Alumni directory and One IMD collaboration platform

Upon completion of an IMD program (Degree program, Open program, Customised Program) you automatically become an alumnus.

Unless you decide in whole or in part to the contrary, the information disclosed to register to the program and made available to your fellow program members during your attendance will remain available to all IMD alumni via the alumni directory, made available to the One IMD collaboration platform and the clubs presidents.

Such information will then be used so as to enable you to keep in touch with fellow alumni and enable IMD, the Alumni office and the clubs to keep you informed of any alumni events (such as but not exclusively webinars, seminars, receptions, etc.).

You are however at all time in full control to decide whether or not you want to be visible in the Alumni Directory, the One IMD platform and to Alumni clubs.

Should you accept to remain visible in the Alumni Directory upon termination of your program, your first name, last name, programs and program year(s) attended will be displayed; you can however decide to display or not additional information and can, at any request, request full deletion of your data from the Alumni Directory.

Changing and updating personal information

You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of all personal information that you provide under your name and to ensure that such information remains accurate and up to date.

Data Retention

IMD will store information about you for as long as you do not delete your IMD Web Community Member account or ask IMD to remove your information. To access your personal information, get any information related to it, or have it modified, updated or deleted in whole or in part, please contact IMD at [privacy@imd.org](mailto:privacy@imd.org?subject=Privacy%20policy%20and%20data%20question).

Upon request, your data shall be deleted from our client databases; provided, however, that such data may remain available in any document generated prior to the request, and shall otherwise be anonymized and aggregated for statistical and research purposes.

Such data may in addition remain on our back-ups systems although rendered inaccessible to other IMD Web Community Members and IMD staff for any business or operational purposes.

Cookies

We believe that the use of cookies enables us to provide you with a more meaningful web experience. We use cookies and other tracking technologies to see which IMD Websites and pages you have visited, for traffic analysis and optimization purposes as well as for re-targeting as part of online marketing campaigns.

We do not collect or store any personal data through these cookies or other tracking technologies.

Should you decide not to have any cookies installed on your computer while browsing IMD Websites, you understand that your experience of the Websites may be limited and that you may not have access to all functions and pages of our Websites.

Miscellaneous

IMD is governed with respect to privacy in accordance with Swiss law, including provisions and remedies contained therein. You may wish to refer to this page from time to time since this document is subject to change.
